<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>c on Joe Buschmann</title>
    <link>/tags/c/</link>
    <description>Recent content in c on Joe Buschmann</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Joe Buschmann 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 01:07:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/c/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling SpecFlow With Proper Architecture</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-08-31-scaling-specflow-with-proper-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 01:07:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-08-31-scaling-specflow-with-proper-architecture/</guid>
      <description>In July of 2018, I gave a talk at KCDC titled SpecFlow: Moving Beyond the Basics. Afterward, I changed the title to Scaling SpecFlow to more accurately reflect the topic. You can find the updated slide deck at https://joebuschmann.github.io/scaling-specflow/.
Over the next few weeks, I created a series of posts, one for each section of the talk, for those of you who perfer blog posts to slide decks. This page aggregates these pages in one place and takes you through each one in order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running SpecFlow Scenarios in Parallel</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-08-24-running-specflow-scenarios-in-parallel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 22:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-08-24-running-specflow-scenarios-in-parallel/</guid>
      <description>As of SpecFlow version 2.0, you can run scenarios in parallel. This means faster execution times and faster feedback in your continuous integration process.
Memory Isolation To enable parallel execution, you must use a test runner that supports it. Available runners include NUnit 3.0, xUnit 2.0, and the SpecFlow+ Runner (specrun). Specrun is a commercial product, but it has advanced features like memory isolation via an app domain or process. NUnit and xUnit don&#39;t support memory isolation, so they requre your tests to be thread safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reusable Bindings in SpecFlow</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-08-13-reusable-bindings-in-specflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 13:44:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-08-13-reusable-bindings-in-specflow/</guid>
      <description>As your application grows, your SpecFlow test suite needs to grow with it. Reusable bindings are essentional to prevent your code from becoming a bloated mess. Fortunately, the SpecFlow runtime has reusability in mind with a built-in inversion of control (IoC) framework and step argument transformations. With these features you can create reusable bindings that make test creation more productive.
Problems with Inheritance Before digging into IoC, I&#39;ll take a moment to cover why you shouldn&#39;t use inheritance in your bindings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working Effectively with SpecFlow Tables</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-08-10-working-effectively-with-specflow-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 21:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-08-10-working-effectively-with-specflow-tables/</guid>
      <description>The Gherkin DSL defines data tables as a way of passing a list of values to a step definition. Gherkin tables use the pipe character | to delimit column names and values. They&#39;re easy to read and understand by both business and technical people.
While they work great in Gherkin, tables don&#39;t translate well to strongly typed .NET languages. They are converted to an instance of the Table type in SpecFlow bindings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SpecFlow Basics</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-08-08-specflow-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 13:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-08-08-specflow-basics/</guid>
      <description>SpecFlow is hands down my favorite testing tool. I&#39;ve been blogging about it since 2013 covering mostly advanced topics. In this post, I&#39;ll go back to the beginning and briefly cover the basics to give you an idea of what it can do.
What is SpecFlow? SpecFlow is a tool that allows you to:
 Define, manage, and automate human-readable acceptance tests in .NET. Enable BDD with easy to understand tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The C# Language - Overflow Checking for Integral Operations</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-12-14-the-csharp-language-overflow-checking-for-integral-operations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 23:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017-12-14-the-csharp-language-overflow-checking-for-integral-operations/</guid>
      <description>The C# language has been around for over 15 years. It started off as a Java ripoff and evolved into its own language. Some parts of the language I use daily: enumerators, generics, async/await. Other parts lurk in the shadows until the rare moment when I need to put them to use.
One such part is overflow checking for integral operations.
Compiler Option By default, integral operations are not checked for overflows either by the C# compiler or at runtime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SpecFlow NUnit3 Generator Plugin</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-10-22-specflow-nunit3-generator-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 02:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017-10-22-specflow-nunit3-generator-plugin/</guid>
      <description>I recently created a SpecFlow plugin to solve a peculiar problem with NUnit test code generation. The issue is SpecFlow will generate test code that doesn&#39;t compile when the .NET project containing the SpecFlow scenarios has a default namespace with the word NUnit. For example, if your project has the namespace IntegrationTests.NUnit, then you&#39;ll receive the following error when trying to build.
 The type or namespace name &amp;lsquo;Framework&amp;rsquo; does not exist in the namespace &amp;lsquo;IntegrationTests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TaskCompletionSource - Bridging the Gap Between Old and New</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-08-15-taskcompletionsource-bridging-the-gap-between-old-and-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 13:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-08-15-taskcompletionsource-bridging-the-gap-between-old-and-new/</guid>
      <description>In the latest versions of the .NET Framework, asynchronous work is represented by the Task class. A task is similar to a future or promise in other languages. You can create one in many ways the most common being Task.Run(). The result of a task is exposed by the Task.Result property. If the work is complete, then the property immediately returns a value; otherwise, it blocks until the operation is finished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 6 Industry Shifts During My IT Career</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-07-08-top-6-industry-shifts-during-my-it-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 01:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-07-08-top-6-industry-shifts-during-my-it-career/</guid>
      <description>In the fall of 1999, I dropped my plans to attend grad school to embark on a career in IT. The industry has changed considerably since then mostly for the better. In fact I&#39;ve never been more excited to be a software developer.
As part of a personal retrospective on my career, below are my thoughts on the top six shifts in IT. By a &amp;ldquo;shift&amp;rdquo; I mean a change that has profoundly affected the way developers go about their daily work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Short and Easy Introduction to .NET&#39;s Task Class</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-12-09-a-short-and-easy-introduction-to-dotnet-task-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 22:09:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015-12-09-a-short-and-easy-introduction-to-dotnet-task-class/</guid>
      <description>Task.Run You can use Task.Run to schedule a delegate to run on the thread pool. The method returns a new task, and if the work is complete, the result will be available via Task.Result. If not, Task.Result will block until it is complete.
Task.ContinueWith You&#39;ll want to avoid accessing the Task.Result property because it will block until the result is ready. In the previous example, the UI will hang for about 2000 milliseconds before updating the label with the result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SpecFlow Tags Done Right</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-10-26-specflow-tags-done-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 13:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015-10-26-specflow-tags-done-right/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I covered scoped bindings in SpecFlow and ended with an example of how not to use tags. In this post, I&#39;ll cover the &amp;ldquo;right way&amp;rdquo; and demonstrate how to avoid coupling features to step definitions. But first, a quick primer on tags.
What Are Tags? Tags are used in Gherkin to mark features or scenarios. They begin with the @ character in Gherkin, but in step definitions the @ is removed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Scoped Bindings in SpecFlow</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-10-22-an-introduction-to-scoped-bindings-in-specflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 12:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015-10-22-an-introduction-to-scoped-bindings-in-specflow/</guid>
      <description>One nice aspect of SpecFlow is the ability to scope bindings by feature title, scenario title, or tag. Normally bindings are global to the project, but a binding&#39;s scope can be restricted using the Scope attribute. I like to think of it as similar to the private and public class modifiers in C#.
Consider the Gherkin below.
It is a single feature with one scenario and two tags. One tag is at the feature level and the other at the scenario level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactoring to Composable SpecFlow Steps</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-09-22-refactoring-to-composable-specflow-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 12:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015-09-22-refactoring-to-composable-specflow-steps/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve seen some pretty bad SpecFlow code. Code that seems to violate every good practice out there. Poor reuse. Copy and paste everywhere. Test code is the hotel room of the software world. People are sloppier and more careless than they otherwise would be. I&#39;m not sure why that is. Perhaps because tests are not seen as &amp;ldquo;real code&amp;rdquo;. But as a testing code base grows from dozens to hundreds to even a thousand or more test cases, having well-factored composable SpecFlow steps becomes critical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidying Up Code with C#&#39;s Using Alias Directives</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-08-18-tidying-up-code-with-using-alias-directives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 21:52:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015-08-18-tidying-up-code-with-using-alias-directives/</guid>
      <description>The C# language&#39;s using alias directives or namespace and type aliases provide a way to disambiguate between namespaces or types with the same name. For example, both the System.Net and Nancy libraries have a type named HttpStatusCode. If you happen to import both namespaces in a file, then the types need to be fully qualified or else the compiler will fail with the error:
 &#39;HttpStatusCode&amp;rsquo; is an ambiguous reference between &amp;lsquo;Nancy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Week in Programming Gotchas</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-08-14-this-week-in-programming-gotchas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 12:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015-08-14-this-week-in-programming-gotchas/</guid>
      <description>We all have those days where we spend hours trying to solve a seemingly simple problem only to smack ourselves in the head when we finally figure it out. Missing quotes, forgetting to flush a StreamWriter, etc. If only we could get back all the wasted time.
Well, this week I wrestled with more gotchas than usual. Below are the ones that burned most of my time.
Streams Don&#39;t forget to flush a StreamWriter when you&#39;re done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>String.Empty Versus &#34;&#34;</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-08-06-string-dot-empty-versus-string-literal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 15:22:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015-08-06-string-dot-empty-versus-string-literal/</guid>
      <description>If you&#39;ve been in the .NET world for any length of time, you&#39;ll eventually come across someone who claims String.Empty performs better than &amp;quot;&amp;quot;. I was always skeptical of this claim because this scenario seemed like something the compiler could optimize. And because the .NET runtime manages string literals in an intern pool, my guess was they would both point to the same value. That&#39;s what I suspected anyway but didn&#39;t have any proof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Async/Await and Recursion</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-03-25-asyncawait-and-recursion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 18:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015-03-25-asyncawait-and-recursion/</guid>
      <description>While using the new async/await keywords in C# 5.0 for the first time, I noticed an interesting aspect to how recursive methods behave when using await. For one method I was working on, Resharper notified me of a possible stack overflow exception with a &amp;ldquo;function is recursive on all paths&amp;rdquo; warning, but it didn&#39;t fail at runtime. Instead, it continued happily calling itself with no issues.
What keeps it from failing is the use of the await keyword when calling DoWorkAsync().</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code This, Not That - SpecFlow Edition</title>
      <link>/posts/2014-12-29-code-this-not-that-specflow-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 20:06:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2014-12-29-code-this-not-that-specflow-edition/</guid>
      <description>In 2007 a different kind of diet book was published that took a concise approach to making the right food choices. Readers of the book were presented with good and bad selections at popular restaurants and told why the good options were better than the others. Eat This, Not That! made changing your diet simple and realistic. No gimmicks like the Atkins diet or the current trend of cleansing. Just real options available in many restaurants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate SQL Delete Statements That Respect FK Relationships</title>
      <link>/posts/2014-12-03-generate-sql-delete-statements-that-respect-fk-relationships/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2014-12-03-generate-sql-delete-statements-that-respect-fk-relationships/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever needed to delete a record from a database table only to be thwarted by one or more foreign key violations? Then when you try to delete records from the child tables you find a deep hierarchal relationship bound together by yet more foreign keys?
I recently ran into this issue with a SQL Server database. I needed to trim data from several large tables that had deep and wide relationship hierarchies enforced by foreign keys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Regex for SpecFlow Bindings</title>
      <link>/posts/2014-10-18-useful-regex-for-specflow-bindings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2014 10:20:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2014-10-18-useful-regex-for-specflow-bindings/</guid>
      <description>Below is a list of useful regular expressions (regex) for annotating SpecFlow bindings. I&#39;m treating this post as a reference and will be updating it with new items from time to time.
Singular or Plural Support singular or plural wording.
Filter for Enum Values If your binding takes an enumeration for an argument, you can limit the inputs from the Gherkin to just the valid values. In the snippets below, the possible values for the SortOrder argument are limited by the regex (ascending|descending) thus avoiding any runtime exeptions due to a bad value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overusing Generics in .NET</title>
      <link>/posts/2014-10-10-overusing-generics-in-dot-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 12:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2014-10-10-overusing-generics-in-dot-net/</guid>
      <description>Generic types were a great addition to C# 2.0, but they are occasionally overused. There are times where calling object.GetType() or passing the type as an argument are sufficient.
A good example can be found in the Specflow source code. The TechTalk.SpecFlow.Assist.InstanceComparisonExtensionMethods class contains a useful extension method CompareToInstance&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;() which takes a table of expected property values and compares them against an object.
The generic type is completely unnecessary in this case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategies for Managing State in SpecFlow</title>
      <link>/posts/2014-09-30-strategies-for-managing-state-in-specflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 18:40:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2014-09-30-strategies-for-managing-state-in-specflow/</guid>
      <description>SpecFlow is an extension for Visual Studio that binds software specifications written in the Gherkin language to executable code written in C#, VB, or some other .NET language. One of the challenges of implementing a SpecFlow scenario is how to manage test state in between steps. At first glance, state management seems like an easy problem to solve, but as your test suite grows, maintaining the implementation is as difficult as any large software project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More SpecFlow Tips</title>
      <link>/posts/2013-07-20-more-specflow-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 11:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013-07-20-more-specflow-tips/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE (11/18/2016):
 I&#39;ve written a number of posts since this one was published that cover advanced SpecFlow topics like composable steps, tags done right, managing state, useful regex, etc. For a list of all my SpecFlow writing, you can click on the SpecFlow tag. SpecFlow is a fantastic tool that&#39;s changed the way I develop software, and I hope it does the same for you. Happy testing!
 My last post covered three tips or best practices for SpecFlow that covered manipulating the current ScenarioContext with extension methods, binding multiple Given/When/Then attributes, and using hooks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some SpecFlow Tips</title>
      <link>/posts/2013-02-17-some-specflow-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 11:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013-02-17-some-specflow-tips/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE (11/18/2016):
 I&#39;ve written a number of posts since this one was published that cover advanced SpecFlow topics like composable steps, tags done right, managing state, useful regex, etc. For a list of all my SpecFlow writing, you can click on the SpecFlow tag. SpecFlow is a fantastic tool that&#39;s changed the way I develop software, and I hope it does the same for you. Happy testing!
 Late last year a co-worker Jay Brummels introduced our development group to SpecFlow a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the Past Year</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-12-31-lessons-from-the-past-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 14:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012-12-31-lessons-from-the-past-year/</guid>
      <description>As 2012 comes to a close, it&#39;s time to look back on some of the things I&#39;ve learned. During the past year, my focus has been on enterprise service development, and thanks to a talented software architect and co-worker Kelly Brownsberger, I feel much more confident with my development skills. Together we focused on re-architecting and refactoring large portions of an ordering service. Now, looking back, three lessons in particular have stuck with me and changed the way I develop software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Singleton Access from a Container</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-12-01-singleton-access-from-a-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 23:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012-12-01-singleton-access-from-a-container/</guid>
      <description>I learned a cool programming technique this week from a co-worker Kelly Brownsberger to enable container access to a singleton.┬á Say you have an interface IApplicationSettings exposed as a static singleton property, but you want to inject it into other classes via a container.┬á The trick is to create another class that implements IApplicationSettings and grabs a reference to the singleton in the constructor.┬á Each implementation of an interface member simply delegates the call to the corresponding member of the singleton reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ditch the Grids and Use DockPanels</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-03-12-why-arent-dock-panels-used-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 19:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012-03-12-why-arent-dock-panels-used-more/</guid>
      <description>I have worked extensively with WinForms and WPF/Silverlight and noticed that docking/dock panels are not used that often.&amp;#160; At least this is the case where I work.&amp;#160; I find this surprising given their power and ease of use.
Using XAML, why would a programmer choose a complex Grid/StackPanel setup over a DockPanel?&amp;#160; Or on the WinForms side, set the anchor properties for control rather than simplify things with the dock property?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Executing Actions Before and After Code Blocks with IDisposable</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-02-14-executing-actions-before-and-after-code-blocks-with-idisposable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 21:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012-02-14-executing-actions-before-and-after-code-blocks-with-idisposable/</guid>
      <description>I ran into a scenario this week where a boolean field was being flipped temporarily to modify behavior elsewhere while a block of code was executing.&amp;nbsp; I have seen this pattern mainly in WinForms applications where data are being loaded into controls, but their events need to be suppressed during the load.&amp;nbsp; Afterward, the events should fire normally.
Below is an example of this scenario.&amp;nbsp; It is a Windows form with a single combobox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Design Patterns</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-01-30-the-best-design-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 20:38:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012-01-30-the-best-design-patterns/</guid>
      <description>The first time I read the Gang of Four Design Patterns book, I was impressed, no blown away, by the brilliance of what I was reading.┬á The Visitor pattern utilizing double-dispatch.┬á Brilliant.┬á Chain of Responsibility.┬á Why didn&#39;t I think of that?┬á Adapter.┬á Simple and powerful.
Of course I was itching to start implementing these patterns.┬á In practice though they seemed to be applicable only in rare situations.┬á Adapter, Builder, Factory, Strategy, were the most useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Crawl Control in WPF</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-10-06-creating-a-crawl-control-in-wpf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 19:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-10-06-creating-a-crawl-control-in-wpf/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I was watching CNN when an interesting blurb scrolled by on the crawl at the bottom of the screen.&amp;nbsp; Normally, the crawl is not something I notice, but I thought to myself, ΓÇ£I wonder if I can implement one in WPF.ΓÇ¥&amp;nbsp; I had never done any animations before in WPF, and this seemed like a good way to start.
So I gave it a shot.
My initial instinct was to bring up Google and see if anyone else had done it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dangers of Mutable Data</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-08-15-the-dangers-of-mutable-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 20:06:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-08-15-the-dangers-of-mutable-data/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across a bug in some C# code that would never have been a problem if the data structures being used were immutable.┬á The data consisted of a .NET dictionary with an integer key and a list as a value.┬á The details below have been changed to protect the guilty.
The offending method takes customer and product objects as parameters and retrieves a list of available pricing for the customer from a dictionary using the product ID as the key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices for Creating and Consuming Modal Dialogs in WinForms</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-07-28-best-practices-for-creating-and-consuming-modal-dialogs-in-winforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 19:37:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-07-28-best-practices-for-creating-and-consuming-modal-dialogs-in-winforms/</guid>
      <description>This is an article I wrote a few years ago after seeing some bad coding practices around modal dialogs in WinForms.┬á Bad habits like explicitly closing the dialog form and using custom OK/Cancel flags irked me, so I came up with some best practices.┬á I hope you find them useful.
Tip 1: Set the AcceptButton and CancelButton properties
Windows Forms have two properties, AcceptButton and CancelButton, for determining what should be done when the user presses the Enter or Escape keys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Blog Post</title>
      <link>/posts/2011-07-16-my-first-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 14:08:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011-07-16-my-first-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve always told myself that I needed to start blogging and get my thoughts out there. Well, after years of putting it off, I finally got started. I decided to write about what I love (besides my family of course): writing software using .NET. I&#39;ll start out focusing on C# and F# language features. I&#39;m proficient in C# but just starting out with F#. Functional programming is very different from what I&#39;m used to; however, I&#39;m liking it more and more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>